## Louis Harrison

5541 South Everett Chicago, IL 60637

M 708.439.3871

<u>Ibhlouis@yahoo.com</u>

Profile

Over 15 years of advanced technical skills with certified training, education and recognized leadership.

Skills

Chicago Stationary Eng. Lic Universal EPA **HVAC** Refrigeration Blueprints/ Schematics OSHA 10

HAZMAT Data Centers (CRAH/Liebert) Ammonia System Operations FDA/EPA/OSHA/USDA training Electrical distribution

DDC/PLC controls operations Plumbing/ Hydronic systems (Chillers) Centrifugal/Absorption PM/CM (Boilers) HP/LP Steam **VFD** Chilled Water systems Water treatment/filtration Calibration./ Pneumatics AHU (VAV. Constant volume Blast-Coolers/Freezers **Building Automation (BAS)** Lighting./Life Safety Project Mgmt/CLT

**PSM CMMS** 

Experience

Utilities Maintenance Manager, West Liberty Foods; Bolingbrook, IL - 7/2015- Present

LEED/LEAN training

Production support mgt.

Managed: Predictive/corrective and preventative maintenance programs, 9-direct report Utilities Techs, HVAC/Refrigeration/Wastewater multi-site mgmt., Project mgmt.(line production, capital) USDA/EPA/FDA code and regulatory enforcing, core management/QA/ leadership training, PM/CM/SOP/SAP/PSM/GMP/HAACP implementations, electrical distribution and plant/production start-up operations.

Utilities Maintenance Supervisor, Arytza; Cicero, IL - 10/13 - 6/2015

Serviced: Utility dept./ production maintenance start-up, 5-direct reports up to 24 indirect reports, HVAC/PLC/ Ammonia Refrigeration PM/CM/SOP/SAP/PSM/GMP/HAACP implementations, and oversaw capital projects.

Chief Engineering Supervisor, Sodexo; Chicago, IL -9/2010 - 9/2013

Performed: corrective/preventative maintenance programs for 5 buildings (1.8m sq. ft.), boilers, electrical repair, water treatment, VFD/air handler maintenance, construction/project engineering, CMMS (maximo/metasys), grounds/lightning, HVAC/refrigeration, fire/safety, generator testing, predictive/emergency maintenance planning.

Journeyman Lead Engineer, RUSH University Medical System; Chicago IL -7/2007 - 9/2010 Supported: plant operations, HVAC, welding, plumbing, medical gas systems, refrigeration, PRV/ high pressure steam stations, chillers/ chilled water systems, offsite data center monitoring/maintenance, and B.A.S.(Siemens/Johnson Controls).

Maintenance Manager, Gate Gourmet; Schiller Park, IL –2/2005 - 7/2007

Managed: start-up for client (American Airlines), team/maintenance dept. (7 direct report technicians), project engineering/construction, conveyors, boiler/chiller/ machinery PM/CM., electrical retro-fitting, HVAC/R (blast chillers /convectors).

Education

PEIT: Arlington Heights IL, Majored: Steam and Plant Operations, Diploma 11/2001 Environmental Technical Institute: Blue Island IL, Studied: HVAC/Refrigeration, 6/1999 Thornton Township: Harvey IL, Studied: Business administration, 6/1992